<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Hailey Gryka</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Hailey Gryka</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Movie Recommendation System</title>
      <link>/2020/09/15/movie-recommendation-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/15/movie-recommendation-system/</guid>
      <description>Movie Recommendation SystemI was recently inspired to create a movie recommendation system when a family member started hosting movie nights during the pandemic. There are some diverse tastes amongst the group of attenties so utilizing multiple genres and movies was a benefit for this project.
This post is a final product of a descent bit of initial data exploration, preprocessing, and similarity testing. Ultimately, the recommenderlab package was extremely helpful, although, I also explored tm and some of the statistical methods available through that package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful R Plots</title>
      <link>/2020/08/16/beautiful-r-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/08/16/beautiful-r-plots/</guid>
      <description>The R language is fantastic for quickly turning data into plots, however, it is not commonly used for creating visual aids for presentation or publication figures. While it is more common to produce final figures with other software, the same quality figures can be created in R.
Herein I show several examples of plots, that I have re-created using R, in an aesthetically similar manner. In each example, I provide the original figure and then the R-code I used for replication, followed by the replicate figure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>